<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cops on ASRG</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/tags/Cops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cops on ASRG</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/asrg/tags/Cops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Police Officers Faces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/police_officers-faces-pof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/police_officers-faces-pof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Police Officers Faces (POF)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;A large-scale facial recognition dataset encompassing approximately 90,000 images of thousands of law enforcement officers. This dataset has been meticulously curated to serve as a tool, equipping investigative journalists, human rights researchers, and digital activists with the necessary means to advance justice, foster transparency, and strengthen advocacy efforts. By facilitating critical inquiry and enabling informed action, the dataset aims to contribute to the ongoing efforts to hold systems of power accountable and promote the protection of fundamental rights.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;Posted: Jun 17, 2024. Modified: Jan 11, 2025&#xA;&#x9;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-274.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Big Lips&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-367.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Mouth Closed&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-536.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Square Face&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-719.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;No Eyewear&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-827.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Arched Eyebrows&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-897.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Middle Aged&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Context&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We live in the age of digital data, and in that age mathematics has become the parliament of politics. The social law has become interwoven with models, theorems and algorithms. With digital data, mathematics has become the dominant means in which human beings coordinate with technology … Mathematics is a human activity after all. Like any other human activity, it carries the possibilities of both emancipation and oppression.” — Politically Mathematics Manifesto, 2019&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
