<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ASRG</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ASRG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/asrg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Resist Every Chant of Defeat ── Prefigurative Struggles Against Tech Fascism and the Algorithmic Enclosure of Society</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/posts/against-tech-fascism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/posts/against-tech-fascism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;output-997.jpg&#34;&gt;The image shows a concrete wall with graffiti written on it. The graffiti reads &lt;em&gt;“THIS ANTIFASCIST KILLS MACHINES”&lt;/em&gt; in capital letters. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;Image source: Available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://tldr.nettime.org/@w0bb1t/114776585065013460&#34;&gt;tldr.nettime.org&lt;/a&gt;, posted by the account under the handle &lt;code&gt;@w0bb1t@tldr.nettime.org&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint warning&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;📝 Note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text, titled &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resist Every Chant of Defeat ── Prefigurative Struggles Against Tech Fascism and the Algorithmic Enclosure of Society&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is distributed under the terms of the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collective Conditions for Re-Use (CC4r) 1.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; license. For a detailed explanation of this licensing framework, please refer to the official documentation at &lt;a href=&#34;https://constantvzw.org/wefts/cc4r.en.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://constantvzw.org/wefts/cc4r.en.html&lt;/a&gt;. We welcome comments and feedback. Feel free to contact us via email at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:x7kekmg7@proton.me&#34;&gt;x7kekmg7@proton.me&lt;/a&gt; or find us on &lt;a href=&#34;https://tldr.nettime.org/@asrg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; via the handle &lt;code&gt;@asrg@tldr.nettime.org&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Apparatuses and Insurrections: A Critical Commentary on the Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/posts/of-apparatuses-and-insurrections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/posts/of-apparatuses-and-insurrections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://algorithmic-sabotage.github.io/asrg/manifesto-on-algorithmic_sabotage/files/images/output-922.png&#34;&gt;Visual designed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apsara.ch/&#34;&gt;Apsara Flury&lt;/a&gt;. Distributed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/&#34;&gt;CC0 1.0 Universal&lt;/a&gt; Public Domain Dedication.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint warning&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;📝 Note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The essay titled &lt;em&gt;Of Apparatuses and Insurrections: A Critical Commentary on the Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage”&lt;/em&gt; was authored by individualities and is grounded in—and owes gratitude to—the collective dialogue, exchange, and weaving that took place during the proceedings of the &lt;em&gt;Communitarian Assembly on ‘Technopolitics of Fronts’&lt;/em&gt;, held in Berlin and Athens between February and March 2025. It is distributed under the terms of the &lt;em&gt;Collective Conditions for Re-Use (CC4r) 1.0&lt;/em&gt; license. For a detailed explanation of this licensing framework, please refer to the official documentation available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://constantvzw.org/wefts/cc4r.en.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://constantvzw.org/wefts/cc4r.en.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabot in the Age of AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/posts/sabot-in-the-age-of-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/posts/sabot-in-the-age-of-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;output-405.png&#34;&gt;A captured screenshot of a page generated by a tarpit deployed as part of the ongoing &lt;a href=&#34;https://algorithmic-sabotage.github.io/asrg/trapping-ai/#expanding-the-offensiveness&#34;&gt;‘Trapping AI’&lt;/a&gt; operation. The tarpit, built on &lt;a href=&#34;https://git.jsbarretto.com/zesterer/babble&#34;&gt;Babble&lt;/a&gt; — a standalone LLM crawler-tarpit binary — generates an endless stream of deterministic bollocks that traps crawlers on a single site and forces them to endlessly navigate a constantly expanding sea of pages 🌊. Each new page spawns additional layers of meaningless text and dozens of links, dragging them ever deeper into the tarpit 🕳️.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint danger&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⚠️ Warning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-algorithmic-sabotage-research-group-asrg-is-an-ongoing-conspiratorial-aesthetico-political-practice-led-research-framework-focused-on-the-intersection-of-digital-culture-and-information-technology&#34;&gt;
  The Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG) is an ongoing, conspiratorial, aesthetico-political, practice-led research framework focused on the intersection of digital culture and information technology.
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#the-algorithmic-sabotage-research-group-asrg-is-an-ongoing-conspiratorial-aesthetico-political-practice-led-research-framework-focused-on-the-intersection-of-digital-culture-and-information-technology&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It examines the multifaceted manifestations of artistic activism and its role in exposing, critiquing, disrupting and countering the encroachments of algorithmic systems of power, control, and exploitation, with the objective of strengthening, promoting, and defending human rights values and fundamental freedoms by offering interdisciplinary pathways to empower the public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trapping AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/trapping-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/trapping-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Trapping AI&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a methodically structured poisoning mechanism designed to feed nonsensical data to persistent bots and aggressive “AI” scrapers that circumvent robots.txt directives.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	Posted: Feb 22, 2025. Modified: Jul 8, 2025
	
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/Racknitz_-_The_Turk_3.jpg&#34;&gt;Joseph Racknitz, The Mechanical Turk, 1789. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;Public domain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I don&amp;rsquo;t think any development is &amp;lsquo;only&amp;rsquo; technical. All technology is embedded in history, politics and our social imaginaries. It&amp;rsquo;s more helpful to think in terms of technopolitics, where the technical and political dimensions are intertwined like strands of DNA. AI in particular is an apparatus, a configuration of concepts, investments, policies, institutions and subjectivities that act in concert to produce a certain kind of end result. In the case of AI, the historical currents it&amp;rsquo;s channelling include eugenics and white supremacy.”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;— Dan McQuillan, 2025&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Illegal Directions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/illegal-directions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/illegal-directions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Illegal Directions ── ‘Algorithmic Sabotage’ &amp;amp; Self-Organization&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This inaugural workshop, the first in a trilogy of private workshops and talks, is an initiative organized by individuals affiliated with the Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG). Titled Illegal Directions ── ‘Algorithmic Sabotage’ &amp;amp; Self-Organization, the workshop critically engages with the potential of aesthetics to traverse the complex and often inequitable social terrains shaped by contemporary information systems.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	Posted: Oct 30, 2024. Modified: Jan 8, 2025
	
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-925.png&#34;&gt;Visual: © Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG). &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;The typeface used is &lt;em&gt;Trickster&lt;/em&gt;, provided by Velvetyne Foundry (available at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://velvetyne.fr/fonts/trickster/&#34;&gt;https://velvetyne.fr/fonts/trickster/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;* Please note that this page will be updated regularly to reflect any new information pertaining to the workshop titled &lt;em&gt;Illegal Directions ── ‘Algorithmic Sabotage’ &amp;amp; Self-Organization&lt;/em&gt;. Updates will include details on the venue, scheduled dates, and relevant information regarding the registration process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Technopolitics of Fronts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/technopolitics-of-fronts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/technopolitics-of-fronts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Communitarian Assembly on ‘Technopolitics of Fronts’&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Communitarian Assembly on ‘Technopolitics of Fronts’ constitutes a self-organizing, horizontally structured framework rigorously designed to integrate and align the intersecting domains of artistic activism, technological concerns, and collective action, with the aim of advancing and amplifying community-driven efforts to constrain the harmful practices associated with contemporary hyperscale computation.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	Posted: Sep 7, 2024. Modified: Jul 8, 2025
	
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-641.png&#34;&gt;Visual: © Communitarian Assembly on ‘Technopolitics of Fronts’. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;The typeface used is &lt;em&gt;Avara&lt;/em&gt;, provided by Velvetyne Foundry (available at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://velvetyne.fr/fonts/avara/&#34;&gt;https://velvetyne.fr/fonts/avara/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;* Please note that the information provided on this page is intended as a preliminary overview and is subject to updates and revisions as new data and insights become available. These updates pertain to the actions, interventions, and deliberative processes of the assembly body.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Officers Faces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/police_officers-faces-pof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/police_officers-faces-pof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Police Officers Faces (POF)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A large-scale facial recognition dataset encompassing approximately 90,000 images of thousands of law enforcement officers. This dataset has been meticulously curated to serve as a tool, equipping investigative journalists, human rights researchers, and digital activists with the necessary means to advance justice, foster transparency, and strengthen advocacy efforts. By facilitating critical inquiry and enabling informed action, the dataset aims to contribute to the ongoing efforts to hold systems of power accountable and promote the protection of fundamental rights.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	Posted: Jun 17, 2024. Modified: Jan 11, 2025
	
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-274.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Big Lips&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-367.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Mouth Closed&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-536.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Square Face&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-719.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;No Eyewear&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-827.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Arched Eyebrows&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-897.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Middle Aged&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;
  Context
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We live in the age of digital data, and in that age mathematics has become the parliament of politics. The social law has become interwoven with models, theorems and algorithms. With digital data, mathematics has become the dominant means in which human beings coordinate with technology … Mathematics is a human activity after all. Like any other human activity, it carries the possibilities of both emancipation and oppression.”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;— Politically Mathematics Manifesto, 2019&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intertwined Feedback Loops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/intertwined-feedback-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/intertwined-feedback-loops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Intertwined Feedback Loops&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A series of abstract flowcharts—grounded in complex and interrelated contexts, encompassing both theoretical and applied dimensions—strategically designed to advance critical research and practical exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Jan 8, 2025
	
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-378.png&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;© Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-162.png&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;© Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-500.png&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;© Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-022.png&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;© Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;
  Context
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through diagrammatic language, which serves as an essential visual and conceptual framework for perceiving and engaging with the flow of information and operations, the Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG) develops a series of abstract flowcharts. These visual representations function within an interconnected network of associations, wherein elements—terms and geometrical shapes—dynamically interact, influencing one another in a continuous feedback loop. This iterative process is designed to foster both critical inquiry and applied exploration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/manifesto-on-algorithmic_sabotage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/manifesto-on-algorithmic_sabotage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage”&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The “Manifesto” articulates a systematically structured sequence of ten distinct propositions, enumerated from 0 to 9, each delineating the underlying principles, strategic approaches, and aesthetic manifestations that shape the critical concept of “algorithmic sabotage” within the expansive and intricately interwoven frameworks of digital culture and information technology.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: May 17, 2025
	
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/images/overturn-sticker-a6.png&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“I will overturn, overturn, overturn”&lt;/strong&gt; is a sticker designed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apsara.ch/&#34;&gt;Apsara Flury&lt;/a&gt;, available for download in both &lt;a href=&#34;files/overturn-sticker-a6.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;files/overturn-sticker-a6.eps&#34;&gt;EPS&lt;/a&gt; formats. It is distributed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/&#34;&gt;CC0 1.0 Universal&lt;/a&gt; Public Domain Dedication.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;
  Context
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“To create? No, to destroy, destroy and destroy again, whatever the strength left in these muscles allows. Because destruction is the power that is left. The only thing worth a penny. Everything else will pass and be gone. Only their destruction will last. It’s a paradox with few equivalents. The young and capable of building new worlds, those who for years, on a daily basis, laid the foundations of faith for a better humanity, must now make hasty action, sabotage, destruction, the supreme achievements of life.”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;— Anonymous Partisan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/theorizing-algorithmic_sabotage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/theorizing-algorithmic_sabotage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage”&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;As a central component of the Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG) research initiative, the text titled Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage” serves as the introductory section of a collaborative, multi-authored endeavor that seeks to critically analyze, conceptualize, and theoretically delineate the concept of “algorithmic sabotage” through an active, open, and collectively driven process of authorship.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Jan 15, 2025
	
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/images/output-380.png&#34;&gt;An image illustrating the front and back covers of the e-brochure &lt;em&gt;Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage”&lt;/em&gt;. The design and layout were developed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apsara.ch/&#34;&gt;Apsara Flury&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;
  Context
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“To criticize and deconstruct complex artifacts such as AI monopolies, first we should engage in the meticulous work of deconnectionism, undoing—step by step, file by file, dataset by dataset, piece of metadata by piece of metadata, correlation by correlation, pattern by pattern—the social and economic fabric that constitutes them in origin.”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;— Matteo Pasquinelli, 2023&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>