<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ASRG</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ASRG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/asrg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Solidarity With the Struggle of Palestinians for Dignity, Land and Freedom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/posts/palestine-2024-03-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/posts/palestine-2024-03-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;57-School-shelter-damage-e1711038408121.png&#34;&gt;Figure: Data published by the UN shows locations of damaged and destroyed schools in Gaza Strip. Schools documented to have received internally displaced people (IDPs) are marked by larger icons (red and yellow). Schools that received IDPs and were also damaged are marked red. The map only shows schools that have been damaged. (Forensic Architecture, 2024)&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt; | Image Source: https://forensic-architecture.org/investigation/humanitarian-violence-in-gaza&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;solidarity-with-palestine&#34;&gt;
  Solidarity with Palestine
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#solidarity-with-palestine&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG) has been and continues to be in solidarity with the people of Palestine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-algorithmic-sabotage-research-group-asrg-is-an-ongoing-conspiratorial-aesthetico-political-practice-led-research-framework-focused-on-the-intersection-of-digital-culture-and-information-technology&#34;&gt;
  The Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG) is an ongoing, conspiratorial, aesthetico-political, practice-led research framework focused on the intersection of digital culture and information technology.
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#the-algorithmic-sabotage-research-group-asrg-is-an-ongoing-conspiratorial-aesthetico-political-practice-led-research-framework-focused-on-the-intersection-of-digital-culture-and-information-technology&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It explores the diversity of practices and the role of artistic activism in exposing, critiquing, disrupting and countering the encroachments of algorithmic systems of power, control and exploitation, with the objective of strengthening, promoting and protecting human rights and fundamental freedoms by offering interdisciplinary pathways to empower the public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Technopolitics of Fronts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/technopolitics-of-fronts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/technopolitics-of-fronts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Technopolitics of Fronts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A broad-based intervention for the militant emancipatory defence of the need for community constraint of harmful algorithmic systems and their surrounding political projects, through the mechanism of the communitarian assembly, a bottom-up, horizontal structure that functions as a means to unite the spaces of technical concern and collective action.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	Posted: Jul 17, 2024. Modified: Aug 30, 2024
	
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-639.png&#34;&gt;Graphic: © Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt; | The typeface used is Avara from Velvetyne Foundry: https://velvetyne.fr/fonts/avara/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;
  Context
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Nothing’s more important than stopping fascism, because fascism will stop us all.” — Fred Hampton, Black Panther Party&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Officers Faces (POF)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/police_officers-faces-pof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/police_officers-faces-pof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Police Officers Faces (POF)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This is a large-scale face recognition dataset comprising approximately 90,000 headshot photographs of thousands of police officers. It is intended as a tool to empower community members engaged in copwatch and other counter-surveillance practices.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	Posted: Jun 17, 2024. Modified: Aug 20, 2024
	
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-274.gif&#34;&gt;The above &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; file contains one hundred randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each of which has been annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Big Lips&lt;/code&gt; face attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In order to protect the privacy of the individuals depicted, the faces have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-367.gif&#34;&gt;The above &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; file contains one hundred randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each of which has been annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Mouth Closed&lt;/code&gt; face attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In order to protect the privacy of the individuals depicted, the faces have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-536.gif&#34;&gt;The above &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; file contains one hundred randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each of which has been annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Square Face&lt;/code&gt; face attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In order to protect the privacy of the individuals depicted, the faces have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-719.gif&#34;&gt;The above &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; file contains one hundred randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each of which has been annotated with the &lt;code&gt;No Eyewear&lt;/code&gt; face attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In order to protect the privacy of the individuals depicted, the faces have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-827.gif&#34;&gt;The above &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; file contains one hundred randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each of which has been annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Arched Eyebrows&lt;/code&gt; face attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In order to protect the privacy of the individuals depicted, the faces have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-897.gif&#34;&gt;The above &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; file contains one hundred randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each of which has been annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Middle Aged&lt;/code&gt; face attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In order to protect the privacy of the individuals depicted, the faces have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;
  Context
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We live in the age of digital data, and in that age mathematics has become the parliament of politics. The social law has become interwoven with models, theorems and algorithms. With digital data, mathematics has become the dominant means in which human beings coordinate with technology … Mathematics is a human activity after all. Like any other human activity, it carries the possibilities of both emancipation and oppression.” — Politically Mathematics Manifesto, 2019&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intertwined Feedback Loops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/intertwined-feedback-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/intertwined-feedback-loops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Intertwined Feedback Loops&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A series of intertwined feedback loops that unfold from several interrelated briefs, which are designed to facilitate intellectual and practical exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Aug 30, 2024
	
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-374.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-162.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-500.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-122.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;
  Context
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG) has drawn a series of intertwined feedback loops that unfold from several interrelated briefs for intellectual and practical exploration. These critically subversive flowcharts have been informed by research on digital labour exploitation, invisible infrastructures, techno-colonialism, automatised technologies of tracking, monitoring and surveillance and many other contemporary phenomena at the intersection between technology and society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/manifesto-on-algorithmic_sabotage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/manifesto-on-algorithmic_sabotage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage”&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A preliminary version of 10 statements, numbered 0 to 9, on the principles, strategies and aesthetics of “algorithmic sabotage”.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Aug 30, 2024
	
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-630.png&#34;&gt;Graphic: © Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt; | The typeface used is Avara from Velvetyne Foundry: https://velvetyne.fr/fonts/avara/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;
  Context
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“To create? No, to destroy, destroy and destroy again, whatever the strength left in these muscles allows. Because destruction is the power that is left. The only thing worth a penny. Everything else will pass and be gone. Only their destruction will last. It’s a paradox with few equivalents. The young and capable of building new worlds, those who for years, on a daily basis, laid the foundations of faith for a better humanity, must now make hasty action, sabotage, destruction, the supreme achievements of life.” — Anonymous Partisan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/theorizing-algorithmic_sabotage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/theorizing-algorithmic_sabotage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage”&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A collaborative writing document that represents an initial attempt at conceptualising the concept of &amp;#39;algorithmic sabotage&amp;#39; as a means of consciously working on artistic-activist and prefigurative techno-political strategies and aesthetics against the necropolitical technologies that reinforce structural injustices, algorithmic authoritarianism and the harmfulness of unrestrained technosolutionism.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Aug 26, 2024
	
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-player&#34;&gt;&lt;video width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34; controls=&#34;&#34; poster=&#34;images/output-924.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;source src=&#34;video/output-581.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;Your browser does not support the video tag.&lt;/video&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;A video disseminated via social media platforms depicted a gathering of individuals vandalizing a Waymo robotaxi in San Francisco and subsequently setting it ablaze. The new Luddites might look like the residents of San Francisco who blockaded Waymo&#39;s self-driving vans, vandalising the vehicles and setting them on fire. The Luddites, it should be remembered, did not oppose technology per se, but sought to &lt;em&gt;“to put down all machinery hurtful to the Commonality.”&lt;/em&gt; The video has been edited using &lt;code&gt;cook&lt;/code&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt; | A command-line utility for concocting and cooking deepfrying recipes for image and video.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;
  Context
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“To criticize and deconstruct complex artifacts such as AI monopolies, first we should engage in the meticulous work of deconnectionism, undoing—step by step, file by file, dataset by dataset, piece of metadata by piece of metadata, correlation by correlation, pattern by pattern—the social and economic fabric that constitutes them in origin&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>