<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algorithmic Sabotage on ASRG</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/tags/Algorithmic-Sabotage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algorithmic Sabotage on ASRG</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/asrg/tags/Algorithmic-Sabotage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Police Officers Faces (POF)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/police_officers-faces-pof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/police_officers-faces-pof/</guid>
      <description>Police Officers Faces (POF) This is a large-scale face recognition dataset comprising approximately 90,000 headshot photographs of thousands of police officers. It is intended as a tool to empower community members engaged in copwatch and other counter-surveillance practices. Posted: Jun 17, 2024. Modified: Aug 20, 2024 The above .GIF file contains one hundred sample images from the “Police Officers Faces (POF)” face recognition dataset. To protect the privacy of the individuals depicted, the faces have been redacted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intertwined Feedback Loops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/intertwined-feedback-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/intertwined-feedback-loops/</guid>
      <description>Intertwined Feedback Loops A series of intertwined feedback loops that unfold from several interrelated briefs, which are designed to facilitate intellectual and practical exploration. Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Aug 19, 2024 Context # The Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG) has drawn a series of intertwined feedback loops that unfold from several interrelated briefs for intellectual and practical exploration. These critically subversive flowcharts have been informed by research on digital labour exploitation, invisible infrastructures, techno-colonialism, automatised technologies of tracking, monitoring and surveillance and many other contemporary phenomena at the intersection between technology and society.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/manifesto-on-algorithmic_sabotage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/manifesto-on-algorithmic_sabotage/</guid>
      <description>Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage” A preliminary version of 10 statements, numbered 0 to 9, on the principles, strategies and aesthetics of “algorithmic sabotage”. Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Aug 23, 2024 Graphic: © Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group | The typeface used is Avara from Velvetyne Foundry: https://velvetyne.fr/fonts/avara/ Context # “To create? No, to destroy, destroy and destroy again, whatever the strength left in these muscles allows. Because destruction is the power that is left.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/theorizing-algorithmic_sabotage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/theorizing-algorithmic_sabotage/</guid>
      <description>Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage” A collaborative writing document that represents an initial attempt at conceptualising the concept of &amp;#39;algorithmic sabotage&amp;#39; as a means of consciously working on artistic-activist and prefigurative techno-political strategies and aesthetics against the necropolitical technologies that reinforce structural injustices, algorithmic authoritarianism and the harmfulness of unrestrained technosolutionism. Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Aug 26, 2024 Your browser does not support the video tag.A video disseminated via social media platforms depicted a gathering of individuals vandalizing a Waymo robotaxi in San Francisco and subsequently setting it ablaze.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
