<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algorithmic Sabotage on ASRG</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/tags/Algorithmic-Sabotage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algorithmic Sabotage on ASRG</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/asrg/tags/Algorithmic-Sabotage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Illegal Directions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/illegal-directions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/illegal-directions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Illegal Directions ── ‘Algorithmic Sabotage’ &amp;amp; Self-Organization&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;This inaugural workshop, the first in a trilogy of private workshops and talks, is an initiative organized by individuals affiliated with the Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG). Titled Illegal Directions ── ‘Algorithmic Sabotage’ &amp;amp; Self-Organization, the workshop critically engages with the potential of aesthetics to traverse the complex and often inequitable social terrains shaped by contemporary information systems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;Posted: Oct 30, 2024. Modified: Jan 8, 2025&#xA;&#x9;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-925.png&#34;&gt;Graphic: © Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt; | The typeface used is Trickster from Velvetyne Foundry: https://velvetyne.fr/fonts/trickster/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;* Please note that this page will be updated regularly to reflect any new information pertaining to the workshop titled &lt;em&gt;Illegal Directions ── ‘Algorithmic Sabotage’ &amp;amp; Self-Organization&lt;/em&gt;. Updates will include details on the venue, scheduled dates, and relevant information regarding the registration process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police Officers Faces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/police_officers-faces-pof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/police_officers-faces-pof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Police Officers Faces (POF)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;A large-scale facial recognition dataset encompassing approximately 90,000 images of thousands of law enforcement officers. This dataset has been meticulously curated to serve as a tool, equipping investigative journalists, human rights researchers, and digital activists with the necessary means to advance justice, foster transparency, and strengthen advocacy efforts. By facilitating critical inquiry and enabling informed action, the dataset aims to contribute to the ongoing efforts to hold systems of power accountable and promote the protection of fundamental rights.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;Posted: Jun 17, 2024. Modified: Jan 11, 2025&#xA;&#x9;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-274.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Big Lips&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-367.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Mouth Closed&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-536.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Square Face&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-719.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;No Eyewear&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-827.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Arched Eyebrows&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-897.gif&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GIF&lt;/code&gt; above displays 100 randomly selected sample images from the &lt;em&gt;“POF”&lt;/em&gt; face recognition dataset, each annotated with the &lt;code&gt;Middle Aged&lt;/code&gt; facial attribute label. &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;In compliance with privacy considerations, all facial features have been redacted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Context&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We live in the age of digital data, and in that age mathematics has become the parliament of politics. The social law has become interwoven with models, theorems and algorithms. With digital data, mathematics has become the dominant means in which human beings coordinate with technology … Mathematics is a human activity after all. Like any other human activity, it carries the possibilities of both emancipation and oppression.” — Politically Mathematics Manifesto, 2019&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intertwined Feedback Loops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/intertwined-feedback-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/intertwined-feedback-loops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Intertwined Feedback Loops&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;A series of intertwined feedback loops, arising from several interrelated briefs, strategically designed to facilitate both intellectual inquiry and practical exploration.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Jan 8, 2025&#xA;&#x9;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-378.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-162.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-500.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-022.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Context&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG) has developed a series of interconnected feedback loops that emerge from several interrelated briefs for intellectual and practical exploration. These critically subversive flowcharts are informed by research on digital labor exploitation, invisible infrastructures, techno-colonialism, and the automated technologies of tracking, monitoring, and surveillance, alongside numerous other contemporary phenomena situated at the intersection of technology and society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/manifesto-on-algorithmic_sabotage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/manifesto-on-algorithmic_sabotage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage”&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;This document presents a preliminary version comprising ten propositions, numbered from 0 to 9, that articulate the underlying principles, strategic approaches, and aesthetic manifestations of the critical concept of “algorithmic sabotage” within the broader context of digital culture and information technology.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Jan 11, 2025&#xA;&#x9;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/images/overturn-sticker-a6.png&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“I will overturn, overturn, overturn”&lt;/strong&gt; is a sticker designed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apsara.ch/&#34;&gt;Apsara Flury&lt;/a&gt;, available for download in both &lt;a href=&#34;files/overturn-sticker-a6.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;files/overturn-sticker-a6.eps&#34;&gt;EPS&lt;/a&gt; formats. It is distributed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/&#34;&gt;CC0 1.0 Universal&lt;/a&gt; Public Domain Dedication.&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Context&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“To create? No, to destroy, destroy and destroy again, whatever the strength left in these muscles allows. Because destruction is the power that is left. The only thing worth a penny. Everything else will pass and be gone. Only their destruction will last. It’s a paradox with few equivalents. The young and capable of building new worlds, those who for years, on a daily basis, laid the foundations of faith for a better humanity, must now make hasty action, sabotage, destruction, the supreme achievements of life.” — Anonymous Partisan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/theorizing-algorithmic_sabotage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/theorizing-algorithmic_sabotage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage”&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;As a central component of the Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG) research initiative, the text titled Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage” serves as the introductory section of a collaborative, multi-authored endeavor that seeks to critically analyze, conceptualize, and theoretically delineate the concept of “algorithmic sabotage” through an active, open, and collectively driven process of authorship.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Jan 15, 2025&#xA;&#x9;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/images/output-380.png&#34;&gt;An image illustrating the front and back covers of the e-brochure &lt;em&gt;Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage”&lt;/em&gt;. The design and layout were developed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apsara.ch/&#34;&gt;Apsara Flury&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Context&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“To criticize and deconstruct complex artifacts such as AI monopolies, first we should engage in the meticulous work of deconnectionism, undoing—step by step, file by file, dataset by dataset, piece of metadata by piece of metadata, correlation by correlation, pattern by pattern—the social and economic fabric that constitutes them in origin&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
