<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Techno-Disobedience on ASRG</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/tags/Techno-Disobedience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Techno-Disobedience on ASRG</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/asrg/tags/Techno-Disobedience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Illegal Directions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/illegal-directions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/illegal-directions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Illegal Directions ── ‘Algorithmic Sabotage’ &amp;amp; Self-Organization&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;This inaugural workshop, the first in a trilogy of private workshops and talks, is an initiative organized by individuals affiliated with the Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG). Titled Illegal Directions ── ‘Algorithmic Sabotage’ &amp;amp; Self-Organization, the workshop critically engages with the potential of aesthetics to traverse the complex and often inequitable social terrains shaped by contemporary information systems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;Posted: Oct 30, 2024. Modified: Jan 8, 2025&#xA;&#x9;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/output-925.png&#34;&gt;Visual: © Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG). &lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;The typeface used is &lt;em&gt;Trickster&lt;/em&gt;, provided by Velvetyne Foundry (available at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://velvetyne.fr/fonts/trickster/&#34;&gt;https://velvetyne.fr/fonts/trickster/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;* Please note that this page will be updated regularly to reflect any new information pertaining to the workshop titled &lt;em&gt;Illegal Directions ── ‘Algorithmic Sabotage’ &amp;amp; Self-Organization&lt;/em&gt;. Updates will include details on the venue, scheduled dates, and relevant information regarding the registration process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/manifesto-on-algorithmic_sabotage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/manifesto-on-algorithmic_sabotage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage”&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;The “Manifesto” articulates a systematically structured sequence of ten distinct propositions, enumerated from 0 to 9, each delineating the underlying principles, strategic approaches, and aesthetic manifestations that shape the critical concept of “algorithmic sabotage” within the expansive and intricately interwoven frameworks of digital culture and information technology.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: May 17, 2025&#xA;&#x9;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/images/overturn-sticker-a6.png&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“I will overturn, overturn, overturn”&lt;/strong&gt; is a sticker designed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apsara.ch/&#34;&gt;Apsara Flury&lt;/a&gt;, available for download in both &lt;a href=&#34;files/overturn-sticker-a6.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;files/overturn-sticker-a6.eps&#34;&gt;EPS&lt;/a&gt; formats. It is distributed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/&#34;&gt;CC0 1.0 Universal&lt;/a&gt; Public Domain Dedication.&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Context&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“To create? No, to destroy, destroy and destroy again, whatever the strength left in these muscles allows. Because destruction is the power that is left. The only thing worth a penny. Everything else will pass and be gone. Only their destruction will last. It’s a paradox with few equivalents. The young and capable of building new worlds, those who for years, on a daily basis, laid the foundations of faith for a better humanity, must now make hasty action, sabotage, destruction, the supreme achievements of life.” — Anonymous Partisan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
